But I had to stay focused and when I got home my daughter sat on the floor.
She was very surprised to see me because she saw everything that happened on TV.
She thought dad was dead because she knew he was there-
-And she thought when I didn't get home that I went there too.
But she did not understand that telephone communication did not work, so none of us could call her.
When I held her, she said:
"Dad hugged me harder and he kissed me a little more, why?".
I didn't know what to say, but the phone rang which was very worrying-
-For that telephone network had been turned off.
So when we picked up the phone it was my husband and now he sounded different.
Now he says: "Everything is gone, it's gone".
The fourth day when he got home he had a note that he looked at-
-And I took it and could read names I recognized.
I asked what it was and he replied that they were gone.
I said "removed from service?." No, they are gone ".
They were killed and then he said, "I don't understand how they died and I lived".
I did not know what to say to him because patients I tried to help have sometimes died.
When it has died, I have always wondered what I did wrong.
I have never thought that they might have been too sick, so I understood what he felt.
But despite that, we became a broken family, we just couldn't talk about September 11.
It was too difficult and we could not accept that this happened in our own country, in our city.
We just couldn't accept it and we lived for about seven years.
The emotions remain, you feel it.
Due to illnesses and they are horrible diseases.
People continue to die too, right?
Yes.
We have had over 180 cancers and Congress only wants to accept 56 of these.
So I mean, there are people who die and do not get medical care because the congress said no.
It does not consider it to be an acceptable illness.
So how many more people have to die before the congress realize that we die?
We die, I don't know where we will be in ten years.
I don't know if you will come back in ten years and interview us, we may be gone.
It is a tough pill to swallow because we will soon have a grandchild.
Tomorrow, right?
"They said this and they said the other".
Go there where the stories are.
Go to the people who lived and experienced it.
Go to the truth!
Conspiracy theories?
We live it!
This is not a theory, it is not a conspiracy.
What was a conspiracy was that 19 men believed in a man's hatred.
They came here and thought it was honorable to kill themselves.
They believed in the theory from the hated man, we don't even like to say his name.
It was a conspiracy, he told them to hate us and they decided they would kill us.
Do you want to talk about a conspiracy?
It was a conspiracy!
Anyone who continues to shoot people because they are Jews or because they are Mexicans.
Those who continue to treat them poorly because someone told them that they are criminals, it is a conspiracy theory!
This is also a reason why I want to make this video so your votes are heard.
Politics has nothing to do with it, it is a human issue.
It is the human factor.
So I guess this is your message or why do you want to do this interview?
I hope that children will see this and understand that you start to start thinking yourself early.
If someone tells you to bully someone and you do it-
-trot that the person has not done anything to you.
Just because someone tells you to do it.
The terrorists thought in the same way.
"Oh, this man told us what Americans did, that and the other-
-So we'll believe it. "
Think for yourself, be your own person.
But we have differences that are what makes us unique.
When I hear from someone who tells me:
"Oh, this is how we celebrate it in our country".
"It is fantastic!
We care and learn more about it.
"Wow, it's amazing! We might take it after that!"
Now that we are grandparents, we want them to bring this with them.
It is the best way to teach your children by learning about other people.
You are never too old to learn, never too old to learn.
It is you!
I want to thank you for this interview.